Hamza Gabajiwala

| (+353) 831446637 | hamzajq16@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | YouTube |

Personal Profile

A Trinity College Dublin graduate student enrolled in the Computer Science programme. Dedicated to building software and writing code to solve modern-day problems. Having one year of expertise in automation and quality analysis and searching for Graduate Programmes in Software Development.

Skills

- Expert: Python, C++, C, Java, PHP, HTML/CSS, SQL, Keras, Pandas, TensorFlow
- Proficient: C#, Flask, Django, Selenium, JavaScript, TypeScript, OpenGL, Bash Scripting
- Fluent: MATLAB, Unity, Unreal Engine, Adobe XD

Education

University of Dublin (TCD)

MSc in Computer Science (ARVR)

Sep 2022 - Current

- Courses: Computer Vision, Artificial Intelligence, Mathematics of Light and Sound, Real-time Rendering/Animation, and Augmented Reality.
- **Thesis**: Enhancing Model Generation using Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs)
 - Utilising synthetic images to solve the problem of data collection and manual annotation on training data, to help the machine learning models perform well on unseen(testing) data.
 - Findings: GANs learn underlying pattens of a dataset and generate new information based on that knowledge

University of Mumbai (MPSTME)

BTech in Computer Engineering

Jun 2016 - Jun 2022

- **Graduated**: CGPA of 3.45/4
- Courses: Artificial Intelligence, Soft Computing, Advanced Image Processing, Data Structures, Big Data Analysis, and System Security.

Work Experience

Quality Assurance Intern (TIAA GBS)

Jun 2021 - Jun 2022

- Independently worked on shifting more than 150 automation test cases from Selenium to WebDriver.io within two weeks with the help of Teamwork and Time Management.
- Actively communicated with product managers to better understand the requirements for which automation test scripts were to be created.
- Received *Pat on the Back* award for reducing downtime in data collection by creating an API for fetching data and integrating it into the automation test scripts.

Web Developer Intern (NDT Solutions)

May 2020 - Jul 2020

- Designed a fully functional Website that went live within a month. Communicated with the product owner for the requirements and made design decisions for the look and feel of the Website.

University Projects

Menace of the Seagull

Apr 2023 - May 2023

- Created an exploration game on the Oculus Quest 2, where players can move around the environment to find mystery boxes.
- The player might find Gold Coins or a Bird in the box; on finding a Bird, the player would be attacked by it. They can defend themselves by throwing rocks at the Bird using the Oculus Controllers.

Holoway

Nov 2022 - Apr 2023

- Created a Virtual Meeting application to allow people to have remote meetings in a VR environment.
- Application works with the Oculus Quest 2 headset and a web application to allow users to interact with each other and objects in the virtual meeting rooms.
- The application was built using an Extreme Programming approach, the team was split into pairs for each sprint, and tests were written before development.

Publications

Conference Proceedings

- Jethwa, Nishant, et al. "Comparative Analysis between InceptionResnetV2 and InceptionV3 for Attention Based Image Captioning." 2021 2nd Global Conference for Advancement in Technology (GCAT), 2021, https://doi.org/10.1109/gcat52182.2021.9587514.
- Gabajiwala, Hamza, et al. "Comprehensive Review of Various Optimization Algorithms for Image Captioning." 2021 3rd International Conference on Advances in Computing, Communication Control and Networking (ICAC3N), 2021, https://doi.org/10.1109/icac3n53548.2021.9725562.